- [Male Narrator] Behind the veil
of all the mystical allegories
of the world's great religions,
there has been a single
great religious truth,
the universal source of all religions.
Hidden in the silent faces
of Egyptian monuments under
the gaze of the Vedic gods,
between the lines of
the old books of Alchemy
and tantalizing us from the
myths of the Aztecs and Mayans,
the essence of the doctrine
has always been there
but few have understood it.
Throughout the history of humanity,
only the elect few were
initiated into the mysteries
of this great universal truth.
And those few guided the rest of humanity
and gave them the outward symbols
of that truth as guidance.
Entire civilizations were
destroyed or disappeared
when the divine knowledge they
had been given degenerated
into desire, lust, greed, anger or pride.
For centuries the knowledge
was protected in this way
but as humanity degenerated
into barbarism and cruelty,
the divine knowledge went
underground and it survived
in isolated pockets around
the world for centuries.
This knowledge is universal and applies
to all true religions
and mystical traditions.
Whether it is the serpent of Adam and Eve
in the Judeo Christian tradition,
the winged serpent Quetzalcoatl
from the Aztec tradition,
the serpents climbing the
Caduceus of the Greek God Hermes
or the serpents of the Hindu
or Buddhist traditions.
All these symbols contain
the same teaching.
The time has come for this
hidden doctrine to be revealed.
(mid tempo music)
The Old Testament or Torah
presents an outward appearance
in the form of stories and histories
and it gives basic spiritual instruction.
But in truth, it is a vehicle
of the inner knowledge
but only those who had the
keys can understand it.
This book was given to humanity
by Moses who was raised
to be an Egyptian Pharaoh.
Thus he knew all the
hidden wisdom of Egypt.
That knowledge is concealed in the Bible,
the Torah or the Tanakh and
in the books of Judaism.
But there are a few with
the keys to access it.
As the Hebrew Zohar says,
- [Female Narrator] "The
narratives of the doctrine
"are it's cloak.
"The simple look only at the garment
"that is upon the
narrative of the doctrine,
"more they know not.
"The instructed however,
see not merely the cloak,
"but what the cloak covers."
- [Male Narrator] The Bible is symbolic.
Because the inner knowledge
has been hidden, rejected, lost
or forgotten, the Bible like
all great religious books
has been interpreted literally.
This is the traditional
understanding of religion,
the outward or exoteric
teachings, the cloak.
But it is only the inner knowledge
that can redeem the soul.
Even Jesus of Nazareth
taught both a public
and a secret doctrine.
- [Female Narrator] "To
you it hath been given
"to know the secrets of
the reign of the heavens
"and to these it hath not been given."
- [Male Narrator] But humanity could not
accept his teachings and
over the last 2000 years,
the esoteric knowledge
that he taught has been
edited out or forgotten.
And those who held
to his real teachings
were persecuted or killed.
(mid tempo music)
- [Female Narrator]
"For narrow is the gate
"and straightened the
way that leads to life
"and they are few who find it."
(somber music)
- [Male Narrator] Though the modern Bible
is greatly disfigured, the
ancient secret doctrine can still
be found in it.
The very first words of the Bible
in Hebrew are (speaking
in foreign language).
The common literal translation
is, in the beginning God creates.
But the esoteric translation found
in the Zohar reads, "In
wisdom, Elohim creates."
Elohim is a Hebrew word.
The root El is Hebrew
for God and is masculine.
The feminine form of El is
Eloah which means goddess.
Elohim is plural
thus meaning gods and
goddesses, male, female.
This indicates immediately
that God is male, female.
In contrast to the familiar
image of a bearded old man,
God is established in the
first three words of the Bible
as androgynous, containing
both male and female.
The word Elohim also refers to angels,
the governors of creation.
These angels are male, female
in the image of their creator.
This is why most ancient
images of angels show them
as having attributes
of both men and women.
Jehovah Elohim is the regent of Eden.
The angel who oversaw
the creation of humanity.
- [Female Narrator] "Jehovah
Elohim formed man from the dust
"of the earth.
"He blew into his nostrils,
the breath of life
"and man became a living being."
- [Male Narrator] Jehovah is
another important name of God,
not to be confused with Jahveh.
The name Jehovah or Jehovah is comprised
of four Hebrew letters, Yod,
he, vav, he and can be read
with many different
pronunciations and meanings,
Jehovah, Jodheve, Jahveh.
Each one very different in meaning.
Yod or Jah can be translated
as male or phallus, Adam.
And Heva, or Heve is female,
mother or uterus, Eve.
And so the Elohim, the
angel Jehovah formed a man
in his image androgynous.
Thus as recorded in the esoteric heart
of all great religions,
humanity symbolized by
Adam was once androgynous,
containing both male and female.
(gentle music)
- [Female Narrator] "And
Jehovah Elohim planted a garden
"eastward of Eden.
"And there he put the man
whom he had formed."
- [Male Narrator] Eden,
the primordial paradise
is remembered around the world.
Eden is symbolic of the
innocence and happiness
that was once the natural
state of humanity.
The humanity of Eden
was pure knowing only goodness and virtue.
Being reflections of God, they
embodied the seven virtues
of the soul.
But Eden is also a real place
although it never existed
in the physical world.
According to esoteric wisdom,
there exists seven fundamental
dimensions of ascending
and descending order.
The ascent and descent through
these realms by the beings
that inhabit them is represented
in the Bible by Jacob's ladder.
When Jehovah Elohim created
Adam, he placed Adam
in the garden of Eden.
This is the fourth dimension,
the world of vital energy.
This is the Yesod which
means the foundation.
It exists in a superior dimension
beyond the physical world.
Adam symbolizes humanity as a race.
And though they were
happy in their innocence,
they needed to grow spiritually.
So Eve was drawn from the body of Adam.
- [Female Narrator] "Jehovah
Elohim took one of man's ribs
"and closed up the place with flesh.
"Then Jehovah Elohim made a woman
"from the rib he had taken out of the man.
"She shall be called woman
for she was taken out of man."
- [Male Narrator] Thus the human
hermaphrodite was separated
into two sexes, male and female
in order that they may
see themselves better
to know themselves.
Since that time, man and woman have sought
to reclaim their missing unity
which is the root of the
craving for sexual connection.
- [Female Narrator] "For this reason,
"a man leave his father and
mother and be united to his wife
"and they will become one flesh."
(mid tempo music)
"And out of the ground made Jehovah Elohim
"to grow every tree that
is pleasant to the sight
"and good for food.
"With the tree of life also
in the midst of the garden
"and the tree of knowledge
of good and bad."
- [Male Narrator] The tree
of life is an ancient symbol
and is found in all the cultures
who have held the esoteric knowledge.
In the mystical tradition
of Kabbalah it is a map
of the universe and of the human soul.
This is the same tree
that Moses found burning
on Mount Sinai.
This is the tree
from which the trader Judas
Iscariot hung himself.
This is the tree under
which the Buddha Shakyamuni
found enlightenment.
This is the world tree of the Maya,
the tree of life of the Aztecs,
the great Nordic tree Yggdrasill
that supports existence
in its powerful bows.
Just as the tree of life
maps the macrocosmos,
the universe around us so it
also maps the microcosmos man,
the reflection of the
universe, as above, so below.
The tree of life symbolizes the structure
of the soul and the structure of creation.
Its roots are in the highest
realms and its branches
and leaves are all the worlds
and the many beings who exist.
This tree gives forth
fruit, life, sustenance,
the light of Christ.
It is even the symbolic
origin of the Christmas tree.
The fruit from the tree
of life is divine food,
blessings for the soul.
By eating the fruit from the tree of life,
Adam and Eve were obedient to divine will,
feeding themselves with divine knowledge
and thus strengthening their relationship
with God in all existence.
This is represented in the
Bible through their abilities
to walk and talk with God
and command the animals
and plants in nature.
Abilities humanity has long since lost.
Having an illuminated
tree of life within means
that one perceives all
the realms of nature
and enjoys the love and happiness
of knowing God directly.
Of this tree, Adam and
Eve could freely eat.
But there existed another tree in Eden,
the tree of knowledge.
- [Female Narrator] "And Jehovah Elohim
"commanded the man saying,
'Of every tree of the garden,
"'You are free to eat.
"'But as for the tree of
knowledge, of good and bad,
"'you must not eat of it for
as soon as you eat of it,
"'you shall die.'"
- [Male Narrator] It is clear
that the tree of knowledge was forbidden
to Adam and Eve yet they
were tempted by the one thing
in all of paradise that was taboo.
The Hebrew word for knowledge is daath.
Daath is the hidden sphere
found in the Kabbalah
which traditionally is never
spoken of nor revealed.
However, use of the word
knowledge is always very specific
in the Bible.
- [Female Narrator]
"Adam knew his wife again
"and she bore a son.
"The maiden was very beautiful,
"a virgin who no man had known."
- [Male Narrator] It is
clear to the observant reader
that knowledge in the Bible
always relates to sexuality
hence the tree of knowledge
is a direct reference to sexuality.
What then is the purpose
of this reference to sex
and its role in the fate of Adam and Eve?
When humanity was physically separated
into two sexes, man
and woman still carried
within them the reflection
of their creator.
Within every male there
still exists a female aspect.
And in every woman an
aspect which is male.
By this level of meaning,
Adam and Eve symbolize
the subtle physiology
of the individual.
The ancient symbol
of the Caduceus illustrates
this male, female polarity
in the individual person.
This symbol commonly associated
with the Greek God Hermes
is visible in the records
of countless ancient
cultures such as Aztec,
Egyptian, Hindu, Greek,
Chinese and Assyrian.
The two serpents have
always symbolized the male
and female energetic channels
that wind up the spine.
As they are energetic not physical,
a scalpel will never find them.
Their root is Yesod in the physical body,
the sexual organs and they
are fed by the sexual energy.
These two channels
of energy are called Ida
and Pingala in Sanskrit.
In the Kabbalah they're
called Ohd and Ohm.
And an esoteric Christianity
they're called Adam and Eve.
- [Female Narrator] "These
are the two olive trees
"and the two candle sticks
standing before the God
"of the earth."
- [Male Narrator] The two
serpents wind up the spinal column
of the physical body.
The spine is symbolized by a staff
or a rod.
The spine has 33 vertebrae
symbolized by the 33 years
of the life of Jesus of Nazareth
and by the 33 degrees of the masons.
On either side of this rod,
the spinal column are two serpents.
Pingala is the male aspect Adam.
Ida is the female aspect Eve.
And it is Eve that drives procreation.
Temptation arose in
humanity out of the desire
to have their own children
without the guidance
of the Elohim.
Eve, the feminine serpent
of the internal bipolarity
is the channel of energy
that pushes for procreation
in both men and women.
Human beings chose to
procreate of their own will.
In their innocence however,
they did not realize
that the laws they were given
were for their own good.
Learning to procreate without
the guidance of the Elohim led
to the discovery of the orgasm.
(dramatic music)
The tree of knowledge or sexuality
was present alongside all the
other aspects of existence.
It is even recognized
as an important presence
in Eden alongside the tree of life.
And in the tradition of the Kabbalah,
these two trees are said
to share the same roots.
However, unlike any other tree in Eden,
Adam and Eve were only allowed
to enjoy the tree of
knowledge without indulging
in its fruit.
- [Female Narrator] "For
as soon as you eat of it,
"you shall die."
- [Male Narrator] While in Eden,
Adam and Eve only knew
divinity and innocence
and thus inherently respected
the laws of creation.
In their innocence, they were
ignorant of the consequences
of indulging in the fruit of sexuality.
Tremendous energy is harnessed
in the sexual act between
a man and a woman.
It is in this coitus
that humanity has the God
given capacity to create.
Man as active force, the
reflection of God the Father,
woman as receptive force, the
reflection of God the mother
and sex as the force that
brings them together.
Sexual energy is electricity
that is symbolized by fire,
by water and by light.
These symbols exist in the
traditions of the Bible,
Alchemy, the Mayans,
the Buddhists, the Hindu, et cetera.
The ancient ritual of baptism is a symbol
of the transmutation of sexual energy,
The source of salvation.
From the tree of life
flow the waters of life,
the waters of the sexual energy
and the force that creates all existence.
All life is born of the sexual waters.
The power of creation harnessing the force
of that electric energy
implies a great responsibility.
It was very important
that the tremendous energy
that gave mankind the ability
to create be used efficiently
because it was connected
to the same energetic force
that sustained the
individual's own vitality.
Not only was it necessary for
sustaining physical vitality
and thus the five physical senses
but also the vitality of
the seven superior senses,
the united mankind to the divine.
At the time of Adam and Eve,
sex was practiced only in the
temples under the guidance
of the Elohim.
The Archangel Gabriel
and his legions of angels
were guiding humanity in this Holy ritual
as indicated by his
recurrence in the Bible,
announcing the arrival of children.
Thus the angels supervise
this Holy sacrament
and guided a single sperm to meet an egg
in the precise moment needed
to engender a deliberate
and divine child.
This is in fact the hidden meaning
of the term immaculate conception.
Immaculate means perfectly clean.
- [Female Narrator] "When a
man has an emission of semen,
"he shall bathe his whole body in water
"and remain unclean until evening."
- [Male Narrator] Sex was
treated with the utmost respect
and the orgasm was unknown
to mankind before the abuse
of the tree of knowledge.
Husband joined wife in the
sexual act in accordance
with the laws given to
them by Jehovah Elohim.
They enjoyed the tree
of knowledge, sexuality
but did not eat of its fruit.
Indulging in the fruit of sexuality means
to spill the sexual energy, to orgasm.
To indulge in the fruit of sexuality
is to taste the divine energy
that illuminates the soul
in order to feel physical sensation.
Thus the energy used to
maintain the vitality
of the individual is
expelled through the orgasm.
Without this energy, the soul atrophies,
breaking the connection with God.
This is the poisoned
apple given to Snow White.
While sweet to the taste
of the physical senses,
it is poison to the soul.
Eating it results in unconsciousness
and an eternity of sleep.
The universal story of maidens
and virtuous heroes falling asleep
is an allegory illustrating
the sleep of the consciousness,
the state in which the human being
loses the direct personal knowledge of God
in the higher realms of nature.
Thus because of the abuse
of the tree of knowledge,
humanity is now asleep.
This is why the fruit
of the tree of knowledge
was forbidden to eat.
- [Female Narrator] "And the
eyes of them both were opened
"and they knew that they were naked.
"And they sewed fig leaves together
"and made themselves aprons."
- [Male Narrator] This was the Genesis
of the distinction between good and evil.
A humanity that knew only goodness ate
of the forbidden fruit and
discovered animal desire.
This is the Pandora's
box of Greek mythology
that when opened, released
the agents of evil
into the world, fear,
pride, shame, et cetera.
- [Female Narrator] "And Adam said,
"'I heard that voice in the garden
"'and I was afraid because I
was naked and I hid myself.'"
- [Male Narrator] Fear and shame
through sex Adam gained new knowledge,
the knowledge of suffering.
In tasting the fruit, Adam learned desire.
From this moment, right and
wrong is filtered subjectively
through his need to feel
pleasure and avoid suffering.
- [Female Narrator] "And
Jehovah Elohim said,
"'Behold, the man has become one of us
"'to know good and bad.'"
- [Male Narrator] Humanity
had already known good,
innocence, purity and simplicity.
Now humanity discovered what
the Elohim had already known
that desire leads to suffering.
- [Female Narrator]
"Desire caused all the gods
"to fall from their places
"and it is desire who leads
all creatures to hell."
- [Male Narrator] Desire is craving
and craving is suffering.
Desire always leads to suffering.
- [Female Narrator] "Desire never rests
"by enjoyment of lust,
"as fire surely increases the
more butter is offered to it."
- [Male Narrator] Thus
stripped of their connection
to the divine, Adam and Eve as symbols
of humanity were cast out of
Eden to wander in a wilderness
of suffering and ignorance.
- [Female Narrator] "And
to the woman he said,
"'I will make most severe
your pains in childbirth.
"In pain shall you bear children"
- [Male Narrator] Projecting
the laws of Jehovah
and the guidance of the Elohim,
humanity attempted to
have children on its own.
And in the end conception
and childbirth happened out
of balance with nature and the
result was pain and hardship.
By using the sexual force
to stimulate desire,
the fire of Eve inverted flowing
in the opposite direction.
The serpent fell forming
the famous tale of Satan,
stimulating the seven inverted virtues,
the seven capital sins.
(gentle music)
Eden exists within every
soul united with God.
Expelling the light of God
from within expels the soul
from Eden and creates a great emptiness.
To replace the void created by
this disconnection with God,
mankind created civilizations,
ideas and religions,
seeking material, wealth,
power, and sexual satisfaction.
Desire for sensation became
the new God and only served
to further degenerate
mankind until man was left
with only a trace of the divine inside.
In story after story,
we find the enlightened
or empowered heroes brought
to their ruin by their lust.
In the Judeo Christian tradition,
long hair was the symbol of
sexual purity or chastity.
Thus when Delilah cuts the hair of Samson,
this is a symbol of lustful seduction.
And Samson lost his power
when he could not control
his sexual desire.
In the epic Indian
classic "The Mahabarata",
Pandu is warned never to
release the sexual energy.
But when tempted by a beautiful woman,
he proves incapable of
controlling his lust
and he throws away his
immortality and dies.
Thus humanity was exiled for Eden
and mankind descended into the wilderness,
the physical world, this third dimension,
the world of suffering.
- [Female Narrator] "He drove the man out
"and stationed East of the
garden of Eden the Cherubim
"and the fiery ever-turning
sword to guard the way
"to the tree of life."
- [Male Narrator] Adam and
Eve were cast out of Eden.
However the gateway back to Eden
and the tree of life was
neither closed nor locked.
Instead, Jehovah Elohim
sent angels Cherubim
to guard the entrance.
The entrance to the garden of
Eden is the same door through
which Adam and Eve departed.
Humanity is not locked out of Eden
but an angel is left to
grant entrance only to those
that have earned the right to return.
And only those that have
conquered the tempting serpent
have earned that right.
(bells chiming)
- [Female Narrator] "If you
bring forth what is within you,
"what is within you will save you.
"But if you do not bring
forth what is within you,
"what is within you will destroy you."
- [Male Narrator] The serpent is within.
The serpent is the sexual fire.
It is a very powerful atomic
energy with a polarity
that can be used either
to create or destroy.
Because this energy is so powerful,
the individual requires great willpower
in order to overcome the
lure of this serpent.
The lure of his serpent
is material pleasure
and self edification.
This tempting aspect of
the serpent is Lucifer
or what in Hebrew is
called Shaitan, the enemy.
Because Shaitan is a fiery
serpent that is ignited
and empowered through the sexual act,
it is always tempting mankind to know,
to have the sexual connection.
The serpent itself is power.
The individual decides
through their actions
whether it will be a
power of good or evil.
It is the difference
between obeying the serpent
or controlling it.
The lesson contained in
the story of the serpent
is that only those with
the strength of will
to control the cravings
of their mind can raise
the energetic serpent
to transform themselves
from intellectual animals
into true human beings.
We must conquer the
dragon that lies within
as religions and mystical
traditions have told us
for untold ages.
The dragon uses lust, passion,
anger, pride, fear and envy.
Thus we have the Hydra of many heads.
In the Medusa, the deceptions
of this circuit are Legion.
The great heroes and gods
always have the serpent
under their power and it is
the serpent who protects them
and conquers their enemies.
In contrast to Eve being tempted
by the serpent causing her to fall,
Moses commanded the serpent
and conquered the Egyptians
accomplishing great miracles.
The Egyptians had
degenerated into black magic
and Moses came to deliver
the true teachings.
The Hebrew Mem signifies water,
Shin is fire
and He is the womb.
So the name Moshe or Moses
means born of fire and water.
The Aztec Christ Quetzalcoatl
and the Tibetan Padmasambhava
were both born of the waters.
Moses then was born again
which means that he
created the soul symbolized
by the illuminated tree of life,
the burning Bush that he
saw in the wilderness.
The enlightened tree unified
him with his inner father.
Thus he received the
commands of God directly.
Moses needed to free the
people of Israel from Egypt.
Israel is a compound word.
Is is from ISIS, the
Egyptian divine mother,
rah is the Egyptian divine father
and el is Hebrew for God.
In this story, Israel symbolizes
the consciousness trapped
in the sinning mind of man.
He was told to take the
rod, the spinal column,
the tree of life in his own
body and it became a serpent,
the serpent of the Kundalini.
His serpent was more powerful
than the negative serpent
of the Egyptians.
Thus symbolizing the
duality of the sexual force.
Only the positive
serpent under the service
of God can free the soul from suffering.
Sex can be lustful or chased.
Sex can create or destroy.
Sex can be animal or worshipful.
Sex can raise a fiery chariot to heaven
or pave a road to the abyss.
Sex is a natural function
of the human being
but only sex as performed under
the guidance of divine will.
Sex performed under the guidance
of the mind creates suffering,
pain and spiritual death.
This is self-evident in those
who seek happiness in sex.
As with any desire of the mind,
sexual desire can never be satisfied
- [Female Narrator] "Through
the abandonment of desire,
"the deathless is realized."
(gentle music)
"And the serpent said unto the woman,
"'You are not going to die,
"'but the Elohim know that
as soon as you eat of it,
"'your eyes will be opened
"'and you will be like divine beings
"'who know good and bad.'"
- [Male Narrator] Whether the
individual is in love or lust,
the serpent is powerful
because all of the blood is circulating
with that fire within the body.
And when two people unite sexually,
the internal polarity is
balanced and enhanced.
A tremendous energy is excited
that permeates the couple
with the power to create.
This is the fire of the
Holy spirit as demonstrated
by the tongues of fire
raised above the apostles.
This is Shin, the fire of God,
the fire of the Holy Spirit
and the fire of Christ.
In this connection,
the couple is appreciating
the tree of knowledge to know.
To conquer the desire of the orgasm
is to conquer the tempting serpent of Eve.
As the serpent is always
on the tree of knowledge
of good and evil, this is
the only place to conquer it
and gain true knowledge through sexuality.
- [Female Narrator] "When
you make male and female
"into a single one, then
you will enter the kingdom."
- [Male Narrator] Humanity
left Eden as a couple
and as a couple must return.
This is illustrated in the
ancient acknowledgement
of the need for both
priests and priestess,
the couple that must work together
in order to reach perfection.
Couples that conquer the desire to eat
of the fruit of knowledge gather
internally all that energy.
And gradually that energy can be used
to create something inside.
Rather than feeding their own lust,
they can restore their own
inner Eve, the fallen serpent.
And from there raise the
serpent of the Kundalini.
They can aluminate the
tree of life which exists
within the human body, the spinal column
and they can create divine
light within themselves
and return to the direct
knowledge of their own inner God.
This is why all
of the world's great
religions emphasize chastity.
Chastity does not mean
abstention from sex.
It means abstention from the orgasm,
from spilling the divine
energy that is the Holy spirit.
- [Female Narrator] "The
sexual act performed normally
"may give a slight notion of the nature
"of this higher consciousness,
"but more than that it
cannot do since the energy,
"instead of being trapped
and put to use is expended,
"creating a new physical body
"instead of spiritual consciousness."
- [Male Narrator] Sex
is not only important
for spiritual advancement it is necessary.
For it is through this
energy that the vehicle
of the human soul is born.
This is what is meant when
the biblical Jesus explains
to Nicodemus that he must be born again.
- [Female Narrator] "Unless
a man be born again of water
"and the spirit, he cannot
enter into the kingdom of God.
"That which is born of the flesh is flesh,
"and that which is born
of the spirit is spirit."
- [Male Narrator] He must give
birth internally to his soul
from the water and the spirit.
- [Female Narrator] "With patience,
"ye shall possess thy souls."
- [Male Narrator] Jesus
of Nazareth never said
that the soul already exists within a man.
Instead he said it must be born
of the water and the spirit.
In all of God's creation
everything is born of sex.
Thus the soul, the fiery
chariot of heaven must also
be born of sex.
The soul must be born in us,
born of the waters of sex
and the fire of the spirit.
When Jesus met the
Samaritan woman at the well,
he told her of a water
that gives eternal life.
- Female Narrator] "The
woman saith unto him,
"'Sir, give me this water
that I may not thirst
"'nor come hither to draw.'"
"Jesus saith to her,
"'Go, call thy husband and come hither.'"
- [Male Narrator] He was prepared
to tell her the secret of Alchemy,
that the waters of eternal life,
the fountain of youth is developed
between husband and wife.
But she was not faithful to one man
and thus she was not worthy
to receive the true teaching.
- [Female Narrator] "But a man
"who commits adultery lacks judgment,
"whoever does so destroys himself."
- [Male Narrator] It is
very revealing to see
that when Adam, Yah and
Eve, Heva are joined
to the sexual fire represented
by the character Shin,
the result is Yahshua, Jesus the savior.
Jesus of Nazareth incarnated
the fire of the Christ
just as did Moses,
Krishna, Mohammed, Quetzacoatl,
Baldur, Zoroaster, Fuxi
Hercules, Mithras, Osoros
and many others.
The Christ is a universal
energy that saves those
who are pure enough to receive it.
Man and wife
through immaculate sexuality
create their own salvation.
(mid tempo orchestral music)
The containment and the transmutation
of the potent sexual energy
can restore the fallen serpent of Eve.
From there, the fire of the
Holy spirit can be awakened,
raising the serpent upon the staff.
This is the Kundalini, the
positive life giving serpent.
It can only be awakened through chastity
and by husband and wife.
A single person cannot
awaken the Kundalini.
The Kundalini is not a
blind mechanical force.
It is the active intelligence of God
and can only manifest
in those who purify themselves
of all that is against God,
pride, envy, lust, greed, et cetera.
The fire of the Kundalini
awakens only with moral progress.
- [Female Narrator] "Unless
your righteousness exceeds
"that of the scribes and Pharisees,
"you will never enter
the Kingdom of Heaven.
"You, therefore must be perfect
"as your heavenly Father is perfect."
- [Male Narrator] Every Hebrew letter
also represents a number
thus every Hebrew word
has a numeric value.
The letters that spell Adam
also give the numbers one,
four and 40.
- [Female Narrator]
"And I heard the number
"of those sealed 144,000 from
all the tribes of Israel."
- [Male Narrator] Only those
who have restored the innocence
of Adam in themselves will return to Eden.
The secret to become the perfect Adam
is in the ninth sphere,
Yesod the foundation
stone, the sexual waters.
The fire of the sexual energy must create
or it will destroy.
This very potent energy
cannot be contained
and if repressed will seek
expression destructively,
internally through the mind, through anger
or through sexual degeneration.
This is evidenced by
the infamous perversions
of priests, monasteries and
convents around the world
in all religions, in
the rampant fanaticism
that has destroyed so
many spiritual movements.
Abstention from sex is just
another form of sexual abuse.
It is very destructive
to the inner psychology
of the human being.
In order to utilize the
sexual energy effectively,
it must be transmuted
into spiritual energy.
This is accomplished by
connecting sexually with a spouse
without spilling the
energy through the orgasm
or if one is single learning
to control the energy through
ancient methods long forgotten
by contemporary priests.
Adam must be born in us
from the sexual water
and the fire of the Holy spirit
otherwise we cannot return to Eden.
- [Male Narrator] "No one
whose testes are crushed
"or whose member is cut
off shall be admitted
"into the congregation of Jehovah."
- [Male Narrator] Entrance back into Eden,
the congregation of the Lord
is through the proper use of sexuality.
Likewise, the entrance
into suffering and pain
is through the improper use of sexuality.
Sex can be used to create good in us
or it can be used to create evil in us.
It is up to us to decide,
do we want to serve the
virgin or the whore?
We cannot serve two masters,
love and lust can never mix,
God cannot mix with a devil.
This is the sixth card of the terror
and we choose our path by our action.
These are the two primary
types of tantrism,
black and white.
Stimulation of sexual
sensation in identification
with lust is black tantra.
Any school or religion that teaches
how to awaken through having the orgasm
is teaching black tantra.
White tantra always teaches three factors,
the elimination of desire,
the creation of the soul
and sacrifice for others.
All white tantra teaches
to renounce the orgasm.
This is the road back to Eden.
Mankind must return to Eden
through same door it exited.
Anyone who wants to be
healed of the damage caused
by the tempting serpent must be healed
as the Israelites were by
the bronze serpent of Moses.
Bronze is an alloy of two metals,
copper and tin, masculine and feminine.
The bronze serpent is created
when the two polarities are
brought together in purity.
This is the great secret
knowledge of Alchemy,
the chemistry of God.
Al or L is God.
Kimia means to fuse or cast a metal.
So Alchemy is the method
to fuse ourselves once again with God.
- [Female Narrator]
"You will succeed at it
"if you take pains to
be what you should be,
"that is to say pious,
gentle, benign, charitable
"and fearing God."
- [Male Narrator] To acquire
true spiritual awakening,
it is necessary to use the
polarities of Adam and Eve
within the human body to
defy the tempting serpent
and raise the fire of the Holy spirit
to create the human soul.
This is the key to the
ancient mystery of Alchemy
to transmute the lead
of the ego and desire
into the spiritual gold
of the consciousness.
When the sexual fire of Yesod
is elevated to the knowledge
of Daath, we returned
to the direct knowledge
of our own inner star,
the light of the world.
- [Female Narrator] "And Elohim said,
"'Let there be light',
and there was light."
- Male Narrator] All of existence
was created with a light
of the cosmic Christ, the
fire of the Holy spirit.
- [Female Narrator] "And the light shineth
"in darkness and the darkness
comprehended it not."
- [Male Narrator] The darkness
of the materialistic mind
cannot comprehend the light of the Christ.
It is necessary to transcend the mind
and awaken the consciousness.
Light is necessary to
see through the darkness.
In order to incarnate
life, it is mandatory
to transcend the animal
desires that fill the mind.
Therefore, one must understand
and act upon the mystery
of Adam and Eve.
- [Female Narrator] "Enter
in through the narrow gate
"for wide is the gate and
broad is the way that leads
"to destruction and many are
they who enter in through it.
"For narrow is the gate
and straightened the way
"that leads to life and
they are few who find it."
(upbeat orchestral music)